What choice do we have?
The world is a cruel place!
I swore... to kill them all!
Every last one!
And just like that...
Everything changed.
At that terrible moment, in our hearts, we knew.
Home was a pen. Humanity... cattle.
Eren!
Eren...
O, my friend!
This is a victory for us!
Our fame starts here!
O, my friend!
Let us celebrate this victory
for the next battle!
"I died for naught" — I won't
let it end like that for you
until I am the last one standing
The enemy is cruel... We will kill...
The enemy is colossal... We will jump...
In our hands we hold blades of glory
and sing in the name of victory
We bear the wings of freedom on our backs
Swearing iron determination upon our hearts,
we slash apart the circle of idiocy
and soar through the sky
with our wings of freedom
Wall: Assault on Stohess, Part 3
brothers and sisters.
Let us pray for the continued
strength of saints Maria, Rose, and Sina.
May they stand firm.
Their grace is a manifestation
of our good faith...
We give thanks to the light
of the divine architect.
He whose wisdom is the mortar;
whose sublime love for his
creation is the steadfast stone.
He, and he alone, protects us from
the Titan scourge, in proportion
to our worship.
Verily... innocence and
obedience are all he asks...
No! Impossible!
Dear God! Please! Not the wall!
Stay away!
Well I daresay it looks like our boy's
in control of himself this time.
Yeah. Still, though...
There's no guarantee
this will turn out any differently
than their last meeting.
Come on, he
wouldn't have transformed...
Unless he knew he could take her this time...
He's got this, okay?
I don't doubt that.
But determination alone isn't
enough to win a fight.
You of all people should know that.
It'll take more
than that to beat Annie.
A lot more.
Damn it!
She's making a
break for level ground!
So much for our gear! What now?
Split into two
teams and go around!
Understood!
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon!
Son of a... where'd
they come from?
Annie... always so cynical...
Like every little thing around you
was pointless.
Nothing
worth a second look.
Every now and then, though, I
could see through the act...
Especially when you were showing
off your fighting skills.
Maybe hand-to-hand
combat didn't count for squat
against our final
grade back at the academy...
But to you? It was a
different story altogether.
Yeah... about that much at least.
It was
obvious you were a liar.
Fighting's your whole world,
but what exactly
are you fighting for?
What could possibly have been worth
all this death and destruction?!
Oh, God...
Section commander, I hate to say it,
but the city'll be debris
and corpses before long...
Even if we manage to catch her.
Well, then that's how it's gonna be!
We're sticking to commander
Erwin's plan, got it?
So stop babbling
and ready the nets.
Right.
Eren...
We didn't
sign up for this.
They... they didn't say there'd be
Titans fighting in the streets.
No kidding. This is crazy.
We've got two of 'em
hashing it out in the streets?
Yes, Sir.
The city's collapsing
like a house of cards.
It's just... it's horrifying...
We can only guess
how many casualties...
Erwin! Your arrogance has
brought hell right to our door!
I know.
I acted entirely
on my own authority.
And I offer no excuses.
You knew what this would
do to us, you son of a bitch!
You knew and
our lives be damned!
Why? Damn you, why?
For humanity.
For victory.
don't give me that!
You're nothing but a traitor!
I ought to kill you right here and now!
None of the higher ups would fault me!
Do as your
conscience dictates.
My post is yours.
The female Titan must not escape.
Deployment is through peer and
Beirer is in command of provisions.
Work with them closely.
Do whatever is required
to ensure she doesn't...
Shut up!
Do... do you really believe...
...this is for the good of us all?
I have faith it's a step forward.
Everyone, lower your rifles.
Place this man under arrest.
Sir!
Deploy all troops immediately.
As of now... focus on evacuation.
Yes, Sir!
Erwin...
I hereby wash my hands of you and
leave you to the high court.
I'll accept their judgment. Thank you, nile.
Levi. For now, stay here.
A pointless death wouldn't suit you.
No, I doubt it would...
Any more than it suits anyone else.
To rise above monsters, we
have to abandon our humanity.
What we fight, we become...
...fire with fire.
Look at her.
Annie can do it.
Annie...
Annie!
I believe in you.
I'm always on your side.
I... will... kill them...
Every last one!
Eren!
What is he...?
Help him!
No! With the state he's in,
it's probably best that
we keep our distance.
God.
She's headed up the wall!
She's trying to escape!
No, no, no! We can't let her get away!
I won't let her!
It's over, Annie.
Now fall.
Annie...
I'm so sorry.
I don't
expect you to forgive me.
But... please...
Please just...
Stand your ground. Stand your ground
even if the whole world stands against you.
Die... all of you... everything...
They'll despise you...
They won't understand.
But I will. Your dad always will.
Oh, no! He's gonna devour her whole!
Eren! Back off!
don't do it!
This... is freedom!
Promise me you'll return...
That's all I ask.
Wha... what's he doing?
Son of a...?
They're merging?
Stop it, Eren!
It's not a good idea
to eat our key evidence...
You idiot.
Eren.
Mikasa... is Annie...?
Damn it!
All the shit we've been through
and this is what we get?
Annie! Wake up!
C'mon, face the
music! You owe us!
don't be a coward!
I know you can hear me!
That's enough.
It's over.
Someone get me a wire net!
This thing belongs
deep underground!
Understood!
What have we done?
If we can't get any answers out of her,
then what was the point of all this?
We're left with nothing
but countless casualties,
ruined lives,
and unanswered questions.
All for what?
Well, it was a valiant effort.
Can't win 'em all though, right?
Right.
At the very least the scout
regiment's been exonerated.
Sure, by the skin of its teeth, but still.
Let's hope the brass agrees.
As you might imagine,
we have many questions.
If the target's identity
was beyond all doubt,
why would you neglect to request
aid from the military police?
Discretion. We had
reason to believe she was
operating in conjunction
with other insiders.
I felt it was necessary to involve
only those well above suspicion, Sir.
Yes. And the price of your "discretion"
was the near obliteration of Stohess.
Well done.
I didn't foresee
the damage's scale, Sir.
Blame my incompetence.
Blame isn't going to rebuild my roof!
If the female Titan
were left to roam free...
The wall was subject to breach...
And the damage to Stohess
would've been beyond devastating.
Perhaps.
Erwin...
You have me grasping at
straws to exonerate you...
What I need is proof that your tactics
yielded some manner of benefit.
Granted, Annie Leonhart is
rendered innocuous,
but also essentially useless.
Yes, Sir. That she is.
Are you saying...
It was all for nothing...?
Hey.
You feel okay?
Yeah...
In fact it's weird how "okay" I feel.
So, is... Annie still stuck in that thing?
Uh-huh.
Yeah... you'd think after all we sacrificed
to get her back, fate
would cut us a little slack.
It's humbling, knowing how far
she'll go to keep her secrets.
Humbling? More like infuriating.
Why'd you let her go, Eren?
You did... didn't you?
You gave her an out.
I know. I didn't mean to, I...
I just couldn't help it.
When I saw her face, I just froze...
Armin Arlelt, and Jean Kirschtein...
You two are up first.
Yes, Sir.
Debriefing time.
See you later, I guess.
Sure.
Honestly... it felt kinda... good.
Just letting go...
My body, my mind, everything...
For a minute it was almost...
Like I wanted to die...
Eren, stop it!
don't worry,
I'm better now.
I'm glad...
I'm glad you're back...
I can't get my head wrapped around it.
This whole fighting fire with
fire business or whatever.
Is that really the
only option we've got?
Not necessarily. Just the only
one that's presented itself.
And now we know Eren can do it.
Yeah, well... if it's that easy for the
fight to turn us all into monsters...
...then maybe we don't deserve to win.
Go on.
No one ever promised us
we'd come out of this unscathed.
For nothing? I believe this latest tragedy
has moved us forward
by leaps and bounds, Sir.
Not long ago, we hadn't even imagined
the possibility of humans
transforming into Titans.
Now, we're not only aware of
the enemy in our midst...
We've managed to capture one of them.
Make no mistake, there are more out there.
And we will hunt down every last one.
The initiative is ours.
Starting now...
We launch an attack on
the Titans within our walls!
The scout regiment's recall to the capital
and Eren's incarceration were rescinded.
Instead, they were charged with guarding
Annie Leonhart in her holding cell
deep underground, where they
kept strict vigil day and night.
Sadly, however...
It would
take a far longer time...
And cost a
great many more lives...
for humanity to discover the true nature...
of what it held captive.